[train whistle blows]
[♪ upbeat music plays]
[Genta, Machu, Shime exclaim]
-What is this?
-[guide] We got some candy.
[Shime] Candy!
[all, in Japanese] Ready, go.
Cheers.
Whoa.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
Oh, man, it looks delicious!
-Tasty!
-[Genta laughs]
[Shime] You downed it.
[exclaims]
[in English] I love it.
-Wow.
-[laughs]
[server] All right. These are the Skaguas.
-Skagua.
-Thank you.
[in Japanese] Ah, I'm sold on this one.
-I think Noel will like it too.
-[Genta] Right.
[laughs]
[♪ music ends]
[Noel] Did everyone enjoy Durango,
a former mining town?
[♪ upbeat music playing]
Today, you will board the machine which
established this town as a commerce hub.
[narrator, in English] Durango, Colorado.
[Noel, in Japanese] The San Juan Mountains
lies to the west of the Rocky Mountains.
The city,
sitting at an elevation of 1,980 meters,
was founded alongside the railway.
[♪ music ends]
This is the Durango and Silverton
Narrow Gauge Railroad.
-[train bells ring]
-[train whistle blows]
[bells ringing]
[train whistle blows]
There isn't a boy in the world
who doesn't like trains!
[narrator] It's the special summer break
Noel organized
for the Travis Japan members.
At the foot of the Rocky Mountains
where the desert winds blow
lies the real America
the members have yet to see.
[♪ playful, upbeat music playing]
The Travis Japan members except for Noel
divide up into two groups
and head to their final destination.
Sedona, Arizona.
Noel sets out to Sedona on his own
before the others
to quietly prepare
a warm welcome for them.
[♪ opening theme music plays]
Travis Japan
SUMMER VACATION!! IN THE USA
[Genta, in Japanese]
Shime, isn't this a train station?
-[Machu] It's a train station.
-[Shime] Sure looks like one.
[Genta] Whoa, What a cute station, huh?
-[Shime] It's a cute building.
-[Machu] This place is darling.
[Genta] Yeah. It's right down your alley,
isn't it, Shime?
-[Shime] I love this vibe.
-[Genta] Thought so.
[all laugh]
Whoa!
Whoa.
Aiyaa!
Aiyaa… Aiyaa!
-Aiyaa.
-Aiyaa!
-[in Japanese] Crazy!
-Sick!
[Genta, in Japanese]
This is Disney in real life.
-[Shime] No kidding.
-[Machu] It's unreal.
[Shime] Just like Disney. Disney!
[Shime, in Japanese] This is insane.
[Machu] It must feel nice to be on board.
-[Genta] It's just like in the movies.
-[Shime] Whoa.
[Machu] It's a movie brought to life.
-[Shime] This feels like a movie set.
-[Machu] Yeah.
[Shime] Never thought I'd see it
in real life.
-[camera shutter clicks]
-I love it.
-[Genta] Mmm, great pose!
[chuckling] Hold on.
You're getting too close.
-I love it!
-Yeah? Is it good?
-Mmm, it suits you.
-Thanks.
[Shime] Whoa, it's amazing.
[Genta] Look at the maintenance worker.
Doesn't he look cool?
-[Machu] They look cool!
-[Shime] Yep.
Don't you think
their work clothes fit the bill?
[Machu] It does.
I'm digging their overalls.
[Genta] It's fitting since this was
the original purpose of denim.
-[Shime] Oh, really? I didn't know.
-[Genta] That's right.
It was made to be
worn by workers at first.
[Shime] Is that right?
-Cool.
-Well, leader, what do you say
-to taking a close look from the front?
-Wanna go look at the head?
-All the way up there?
-Yep.
-Wanna get right up to it?
-Shall we walk that way?
-Let's see how close we can get.
-Should we?
-Yeah.
-Since we're here, why not?
Good point.
What a beast of a machine.
-It's seriously wild.
-Yeah, this is incredible.
-Just wow.
-[Genta] How fascinating.
Have a safe trip!
See you! Bye-bye!
[train whistle blows]
-[Genta] Amazing.
-[Shime] It's seriously cool.
[train whistle blows]
-[Machu] Whoa.
-[Shime] It's amazing, really.
-[Machu] It packs a punch!
-[Shime] Oh, look. They're waving at us.
[train whistle blows]
[Genta] Bye-bye!
[Machu cheers]
[Machu, in English] Yeah!
-[Genta, in Japanese] Wow.
-[Machu] It goes on forever.
-[Genta] It's so long.
-[Machu] It keeps going too.
[Shime] So many compartments
strung together.
-Everyone's waving at us.
-[Genta] Have a safe trip, everyone!
[Shime]
Are they about to connect the cars?
[Machu] Looks like it.
They're docking.
-[Genta, in English] Oh, yeah!
-Oh, yeah!
-[cheers] Yeah!
[Genta, in Japanese] Docking! [cheers]
[Machu] Docking.
[Shime, in English] Yeah!
[train bells ringing]
-[in Japanese] Now I'm hyped.
-Seriously, yeah.
What a treat.
-They're selling helmets, Shime.
-Oh, actually?
-Helmets.
-You're right.
[♪ playful, upbeat music playing]
[Genta] It suits you.
-I love it.
-Nice.
[Genta] Nice.
You two should definitely buy it.
-[Machu] It's your colors too.
-It's my TJ color.
Look at this tiny one.
-[Shime] What's the tiny one gonna do?
-It's the inside bumper of the helmet.
[Shime] Hmm, I might grab a mug from here.
[Genta] Knew it.
Are those collectibles?
Shime, you've got like 800 mugs at home.
-Seriously, I've got a huge collection.
-[Genta laughs]
I prefer mugs over utensils
and ornate dishes.
-I love it. It's a good keepsake.
-Right?
I'm thinking this one.
It has the train on it.
[Machu] Oh, you're right.
[Shime] How cute.
Mmm.
[Shime, in English] 20.74.
[in Japanese] Then… this one.
-[in English] Thank you.
-[Machu, in Japanese] It's really cute.
I'm happy with this purchase.
-[Genta] Isn't this crazy, or what?
-This is nuts.
-[Genta] It's outta this world.
-This is wild.
-[Genta] Are you excited?
-Oh, very.
-[Genta] Not exaggerating?
-It's too close!
[in English]
You guys wanna come in the engine?
Oh, yeah.
-Come on.
-Let's go. Come on!
-Let's go!
-[in Japanese] Whoa, no way.
-It's massive.
-Whoa, we get to hop onboard!
Wowee.
[conductor, in English]
Come up the ladder.
Okay.
[in Japanese] This is sick.
[in English] Ooh!
Whoa!
-[conductor] Everything's burning hot.
-[Machu, in Japanese] Whoa, no way.
[in English] Wow.
-[Shime, in Japanese] I can't believe it.
-[in English] Awesome.
[Genta, Machu, Shime, in Japanese] Whoa!
[Machu] This is how the engine
is powered up.
[Genta] Does it go, "choo-choo?"
Choo-choo.
-[Shime, in English] I wanna try… Yeah.
-[conductor] Blow the whistle?
We'll do that later.
If I blow that now, it means something.
-[Machu] Okay, later.
-[Shime] Ah, okay.
-[conductor] It would confuse everybody.
-Okay.
-[in Japanese] Whoa, no way.
-It's sick.
[Shime] I'm blown away.
[Genta] What a special experience.
[conductor, in English] Yes.
These are all the engineer's controls.
-Got all of our brakes. Brake systems.
-[Shime] Uh-huh.
-Brake. Okay.
-[Genta] Oh.
-This is our gas pedal and throttle.
-[Machu] Okay.
And then this is how we change direction.
To go forward, go backward.
[Machu, in Japanese] This is how
the train engineer controls the train.
[Shime] Who knew. How amazing.
[in English] This is Lane.
He's our fireman.
[Genta] Hi.
He sits here and controls the fuel,
and makes the fire bigger and smaller,
-and adjust the steam pressure.
-[Shime] Okay.
Puts water in the boiler.
[Machu] What is this?
[conductor] Oh, all of these? Yeah.
So, these are all valves that control
different aspects of the engine.
-[Machu] Uh-huh.
-Um, they're just main shut-offs.
So, we can shut steam off to an appliance
if something were to, you know,
break open or something.
Uh, if we need to isolate something,
we can do that.
-[Machu] Uh-huh.
-Um, this is just a vent.
It opens up the roof
so it doesn't get so hot.
[Machu] Ah, I see, I see.
[conductor] It's still hot,
but that kind of helps.
-[Genta] Uh-huh.
-[conductor] Um…
and then this is steam pressure
in the boiler.
-[Genta] A boiler.
-[Machu] Boiler. Ah, I see.
[Genta] Cool.
[in Japanese]
Man, this is really exciting.
-[Genta] Whoa, this is cool.
-Right?
-Normally, you can't access this area.
-[Genta] Right?
-I'm over the moon.
-We're super excited!
-[Genta] Shime-chan's stoked.
-[in English] Let's go!
[Genta, in Japanese] Here we go.
-[in English] Thank you.
-[conductor] Yeah.
Thank you so much.
-Appreciate it.
-Yeah, no problem.
[Machu] Thank you.
[Genta] Whoo.
-There you go.
-Thank you so much.
-Turn around.
-Turn around. Thank you.
-Thank you. Good job.
-Thank you.
-Thank you so much.
-Sure, have fun.
[in Japanese] How cool.
It's not every day you get to…
What a special experience.
-…see the steam engine up close.
-Right?
-That was crazy.
-Seriously.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
-Well, shall we board the train?
-[Shime] Is it time?
[Machu] Let's go.
-[in English] Hello.
-Hello.
[Machu, in Japanese] Yes, let's.
-[in English] Oh, yeah.
-[in Japanese] Hup-ho.
[Shime] Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[Machu, in English] Hello.
[Genta] Oh, yeah.
[in Japanese] Wowza. [in English] Hi.
-[passengers] Hi.
-[Shime] Hello.
[Genta] Hello. Hello.
[Machu, in Japanese]
Whoa, no freaking way.
[Shime] Right?
[Machu] I need a minute to take it all in.
This is too much.
Nice greenery. [sighs]
[♪ music ends]
[conductor, in English]
Welcome aboard the Durango and Silverton.
We are a 45-mile historic narrow gauge
railroad here in Southwestern Colorado.
These carts do tend to
rock and roll around quite a bit.
We are what's called
a narrow gauge railroad.
So, everything kind of moves around
a little bit more
than on a regular railroad.
Sound good, guys?
-Yeah.
-[Machu] Okay.
-All right. Have fun today, all right?
-[all] Thank you so much.
-[train bells ring]
-[whistle blows]
Bye-bye.
-Yeah. Bye-bye.
-Bye.
[Machu, in Japanese] I love the open view.
[Shime] Me too.
[train whistle blows]
[Genta whoops]
Whoa.
-It doesn't get any better than this.
-[Machu] Whoa, sick!
[Shime] Dope, right?
The sound and the rocking of the tracks
-are soothing.
-I love it.
-You having fun?
-Oh, very.
-I heard there's a concession on board.
-Oh, really?
-Yep.
-Wanna go check it out?
-Yeah.
-The concession… as in, the trolley lady?
Maybe the worker comes around too, yeah.
-That's what it means, right?
-Yeah, shall we head to it?
[Shime] These are our tickets.
The ticket inspector's coming around.
-[Machu] Oh, really?
-[Shime] Mm-hmm.
[Genta] These tickets are huge.
-Oh! Oh! What?
-[Shime] Whoa.
Careful, watch out for your hands.
[Machu] Will do. What a breathtaking view!
-[Genta] It's magnificent.
-[Shime] Yeah, the water's pristine.
I was taking in the rocking train,
the breeze, and this majestic scenery.
Whoa, whoa!
What's that over there?
[Genta] Hey!
[Machu] They're having a blast
out on the water.
[Shime] They're having a swell time.
-I want to try my hands at it.
-[Genta] I love this.
[Machu] I wanna give it a whirl!
I love it. Looks real nice, huh?
[chuckling] It's amazing.
It looks really fun.
Hello!
-[Machu] Hello!
-[Genta, in English] Hey!
[Machu, in Japanese] Hello there!
[Shime] Amazing.
Are those cows?
[Machu] Cows!
Moo!
We're way up in the mountains.
[Genta] We totally are.
[Shime] Over here, too.
[train whistle blows]
-[cheers]
-[Genta] Whoo!
[Machu, Shime, in English] Yeah!
[in Japanese] It's the best!
[train whistle continues]
[Machu, in English] Yeah!
[in Japanese] I love Durango!
[all laugh]
[♪ upbeat western music playing]
What a view.
-Here he comes.
-[in English] Wow!
[Genta, in Japanese]
Get your tickets ready.
[in English] Hey.
-Thank you.
-Yeah. Thank you.
[in Japanese] Amazing.
-[Genta, in English] Yeah.
-[Shime, in Japanese] Yep.
This is wicked cool.
Whoa, this is, um…
-I'm bringing it home.
-Me too.
I'm gonna put it up on my wall.
-[Genta] It's a good memory.
-It's a good keepsake.
[narrator] As the name suggests,
the Durango and Silverton
Narrow Gauge Railroad
connects the 72-kilometer distance
between Durango and Silverton.
First established in 1881 to service
both the San Juan Mine and the passengers,
the steam locomotive
is now a major tourist attraction.
[in English]
The railroad was built in 1881 and 1882.
Mm-hmm.
Silverton had a large deposit of silver,
smaller deposit of gold,
smaller deposit of copper.
But they needed a way to get…
It's 50 miles or 48 miles.
The-- They couldn't pack the stuff in
by a mule…
Mm-hmm.
…so the railroad,
the Denver and Rio Grande railroad,
built this railroad in 1881.
And then they brought in some engines.
The engines that you saw today…
[train engine hisses]
They… The mines still have silver,
still have gold…
Oh.
…but it cost more to mine it,
to dig it up…
Uh-huh.
…and process it, than it's worth
after it gets poured into bricks.
So, there's… It…
The mining stopped in 1947 or 1948.
-But…
-This railroad was built for mining?
-It was built for mining.
-Mining. And then after it changed?
The mining stopped? And for…
-So now it's just been…
-Sightseeing?
But it's been, like, passengers only,
but a couple of trains a day,
or several trains a day.
And the… the people
wouldn't let the railroad destroy it, so…
In the meantime,
the… the railroad, to generate money,
initiated some passenger trips.
And the passenger trips were so,
excuse me, were so popular that
when they finally shut down the mining,
they were going to tear up the tracks,
but the people that were riding it
as passengers or as sightseers were…
just said, "Hey, this is so great to see,
that you can't tear it up."
So, consequently,
it's a 100-year-old locomotive
that's been operating nonstop.
-[train bells ringing]
-[engine hisses]
[♪ gentle music playing]
[guide] Four years in a row,
this has been chosen as the
most scenic railroad in the United States.
-Ooh. [stutters] This right here? [gasps]
-This right here.
[narrator, in Japanese]
Following the California gold rush
in the mid-19th century,
settlers who pushed inland
established the San Juan Mine.
The mining boom for gold and silver
brought rapid economic growth
to this region.
The mine reached its peak
in the late 1800s.
This steam-powered locomotive
will whisk you away
to days redolent of the Old Frontier.
-[train bells ringing]
-[engine chugging]
[♪ music ends]
[train whistle blowing]
[in Japanese] This is sublime.
It is. It's just like a movie.
-Yeah, it's like we stepped into a movie.
-I agree.
Yep.
Not to mention
we're under this vast, blue sky.
This is peak happiness.
Seriously, it's Disneyland,
except it's real.
[Genta] Oh, no joke.
[Shime] It's like Big Thunder Mountain.
-[Machu] Look at this rock wall.
-[Shime] Whoa!
[Genta] Whoa! Ah.
It's Big Thunder Mountain brought to life.
-No kidding.
-[in English] Oh, yeah!
-[in Japanese] We're so close.
-We're right against the rock wall.
-[Shime] I don't believe this.
-Incredible.
Seriously,
I can't believe all of this exists.
I love it.
[train chugging]
-And this open view too.
-[Genta] No kidding.
-[Shime] This sheer vastness.
-[Machu] Yeah, so vast.
[train whistle blows]
[Genta] Whoa! Look, look, look.
[Machu] Whoa! Hey!
Incredible!
[train whistle blowing]
[Machu, Shime whooping]
-Yeah!
-Train ride's the best!
[Machu] This is exhilarating!
[Genta] Phew!
[Shime] Man, what a pleasant ride.
-Here comes.
-One.
There it is!
This is just like Disney.
[Machu] It's dope.
[Genta] We're right up against the walls!
We can almost touch it.
[Genta, in English] Wow.
[Machu] Wow.
-[Machu, in Japanese] It's wild turquoise.
-[Genta] Wild turquoise!
This is impressive.
-Whoa, whoa! Amazing!
-Whoa, what a majestic view!
-[Genta] Hey, look!
-[Machu] Hey.
-[Genta] Real talk, I'm touched.
-[Machu] Real talk, I'm moved too.
[Shime] Crazy.
[all, in English] Yeah!
[Machu, in Japanese]
No freaking way! [laughs]
[Genta] Whoa, whoa, whoa!
-[Machu] Hey, this is seriously crazy!
-[Shime] What an ethereal view.
[Genta] This may be
the most photogenic location yet.
[Shime]
Look at the beautiful river flowing below.
[Machu] It's like a postcard.
What a grand view.
[exhales deeply]
[Shime] This is incredible, really.
[Machu]
I've got to see it with my own eyes.
-[Shime] How pretty.
-[Genta] My contact lenses.
-Take out your contacts.
-[Machu] Yeah, I'm taking them out.
Crazy. Just insane!
[Shime] It's exhilarating!
[Genta chuckling] It's unreal.
[Machu] Whoa, I'm scared.
[Genta] This is the best.
This is invigorating.
-Right?
-I know what you mean.
Behold the healing power of nature.
It's amazing.
It really is amazing.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
[Genta] Shoot!
[Shime] Honestly, it's…
[in English] …beautiful.
[Genta, in Japanese] So pretty.
[in English] Beautiful.
[Machu, in Japanese]
I bet this place is teeming with wildlife.
-[Genta] You're absolutely right.
-[Machu] Mm-hmm.
[Machu] That's almost a given.
[Genta] What if there are bears?
-I wouldn't be surprised.
-[Genta] Yep.
[in English]
Are we having a good time today, guys?
-Yes. I have a good time.
-All right. Yeah.
Well, we're glad to have you
on the Durango-Silverton trail.
This is
one of the most authentic railroads
to how it was done back in the 1880s
in the United States.
Even down to the way that we dress.
-Uh, my uniform today is pretty much…
-[Genta] Nice.
…what guys a hundred and--
140 years ago would've been wearing
on this branch line.
Even down to the pocket watch
that I carry.
-But this one's a little special to me…
-[Genta] Oh. So cool.
…because this was a gift to me
from my dad.
And, uh, he gave it to me
when I was a little kid.
And I carry it with me every day to
let him know that I'm thinking about him.
-[Machu] Oh, nice. So cute.
-Yeah, well…
[Shime, in Japanese] What's the
most important part about this job?
[in English]
Most important thing about this job
is that I get to do something
that I've always wanted to do.
This is what I wanted to do
from the time I was a little kid.
And the fact that
I get to come to work every day
and do something that I absolutely love
is really, really great.
[in Japanese]
When did the steam train begin service?
[in English] This train has been
running continuously for 143 years.
-[Genta] Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
-This line was opened in 1882
and every year there has been trains
running on this line up to Silverton.
-Oh. Oh.
-Ah.
[in Japanese]
Quite a long history, then. 1880?
This train dates way back. 40…
[in English] There was a period
when the train ran only twice a week.
-[Machu] Uh-huh.
-[Shime] Twice a week?
Just twice a week. Tuesdays and Saturdays.
[Genta] Uh-huh.
But then tourism picked up
in this area in the mid-1950s
and the train started running
every day then.
[Genta] Wow.
And this railroad has survived
two floods, um, economic disaster,
um, the collapse of the mining industry,
the Great Depression
and it still soldiered on
-through these mountains.
-[Genta] Wow.
-[in Japanese] How inspiring.
-[in English] So cool.
[conductor]
I mean, like, it is pretty cool.
-It's definitely very different.
-Yeah.
You won't find another railroad
like this anywhere in the world.
-Mmm.
-Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Wow.
A couple places rival it,
but this place is pretty spectacular.
-[Shime] Wow.
-[Machu] Uh-huh.
[Machu, in Japanese]
Do you get a lot of snow in this region?
[in English] Uh, yes.
We do get a lot of snow, and we, uh…
we do run the train in the winter as well.
And we'll put a snowplow
on the front of the engine
to clear the snow off of the tracks
in the wintertime.
-Really fun to see that happening.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I see.
[in Japanese]
It can't be easy. Dealing with the snow.
Have you seen a Christmas movie
with a train in it?
-There's always a snowplow at the front.
-Right.
-Right, right, right.
-It has the plow attached.
That's so true. Yeah.
-That thing.
-I'd reckon, yeah.
It's incredible.
I'll bet the experience is different
with snow.
-[Genta] Yeah, I bet you're right.
-[Machu] The scenery would change too.
[in English] We're gonna be coming up here
to a bridge, guys.
-[Machu] Oh, really?
-You'll to be able to see it
through the trees here.
The bridge is 130 years old…
-Wow.
-…and it's gonna, uh,
gonna take us
to the other side of the river.
And it's over 100 feet long.
And there's a curved section to it
on the north end.
So, there's wood and steel sections
of this bridge that we're gonna cross.
Right.
Bridge.
[Machu] Whoa.
[Genta, in Japanese] Incredible.
[whoops]
[Machu] Whoa!
Fantastic.
[Genta] It feels incredible.
[Machu] How nice.
[Shime] The water is crystal clear.
[Machu] Everything is breathtakingly
beautiful and refreshing.
-[Genta] Yeah.
-[Shime] Mm-hmm.
[♪ serene music playing]
[♪ music continues]
[♪ music stops]
[train chugging]
[Genta, in Japanese] Shall we go
take a look at their drink selection?
-Let's go hit up the shop. Yeah?
-[Machu] Let's go.
-[Genta] Wanna go check it out?
-Wanna go check it out?
-I wonder what they serve.
-Yeah.
Thanks.
-It's a shaky ride.
-[Genta] We're rocking.
[Genta, in English] Thank you.
-[in Japanese] Awesome.
-Right?
-[Machu] What a nice scent.
-[Genta] Yeah, the smell is heavenly.
I've seen train stands
like this in movies.
-[Genta] It's so cool.
-[Machu] Right?
-They carry all sorts of drinks.
-Yeah, I've seen this in movies.
I wonder if they serve coffee here.
-[Genta] Oh, coffee sounds good.
-Good idea.
For me, Coke maybe.
-I love this vibe.
-Right?
-[server, in English] Hi, my friends.
-Hi.
-[server] How are you guys?
-Great.
Really good.
So, could I get Coke please?
[server] A Coke?
The blue bar down at the bottom.
Uh, could I get coffee?
-[server] Coffee?
-Yes, please. Thank you.
-[server] Do you like cream or sugar?
-No, black.
-[server] Just black? You got it.
-Yes, thanks so much.
[server]
I'll fill it all the way to the top.
-Yeah.
-[train whistle blows]
Can I get a water?
-[server] A water?
-Yeah.
It'll be in that refrigerator
right there for you at the bottom.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
-[server] Absolutely.
-Thank you.
[in Japanese] They serve it here.
[train chugging]
[train whistle blows]
[♪ upbeat music playing]
[in English] Yeah. Hot dog!
-Yeah.
-[in Japanese] Nice!
[in English] Thank you.
-Hot dog.
-[in Japanese] Thanks.
This is the best.
[in English] And then…
[in Japanese] Here you go.
[in English] Oh, thank you.
-[in Japanese] Here.
-[in English] Thank you.
[Genta, in Japanese] This is the best.
[Shime] Heck yeah!
[Machu, in English] Oh, yeah!
Oh, yeah.
[Shime, in Japanese] Bon appétit!
-[Machu, in English] Oh, yeah.
-[Genta] Oh, yes.
[in Japanese] Don't eat without me, bro!
I'll wait for you, bro.
I'll wait as long as you want me to, bro!
-Wait, wait!
-Wait for me!
-Take it easy, my man.
-[in English] Oh, yeah!
[in Japanese] Time to dig in!
-Time to dig in!
-Digging in.
Yum!
Scrumptious.
The sausage's a killer.
Delish.
It's fantastic!
So yummy!
Scrumptious!
Best hot dogs ever!
[Genta, Machu laugh]
-Your voice squeaked.
-[Machu laughs]
-This is crazy.
-Crazy!
[Machu] It's the best.
[Shime] This really is the best.
-Mmm.
-[Genta] Mmm.
Time to take a bite.
[Genta] It's amazing.
[Machu] This is the best.
Yum.
[Genta] It's the best. What a nice breeze.
[Machu shouting] It's the best.
What a nice breeze!
[Shime whoops]
[Machu] Are you getting hot?
-[Genta] It's the best.
-[Machu] Oh, this is pure bliss.
[Genta] I'm loving it.
The bestest ever.
Let's shout toward the valley, okay?
[Genta, Machu] Ready, go.
[all shouting]
Thanks for the scrumptious meal!
[♪ music ends]
[train whistle blowing]
[Genta] We stopped.
[static on radio]
We stopped.
[chattering on radio]
Have we arrived?
Is this it?
[Shime] Maybe.
[Genta] Even our stop screams America.
[Machu laughs]
It's not flat.
-[Genta] Wow…
-[Machu] Wow.
[passenger speaking indistinctly
in English]
[Machu, in Japanese] Whoa!
-[Genta] Wow.
-[Shime] Amazing.
Wow!
-[Genta] This is incredible.
-Amazing.
[chattering on radio]
That's how the switch stand works.
-Yeah. Cool, huh?
-Cool.
It's wicked cool.
[Machu] Huh.
Amazing.
That's impressive.
Yes, now we're facing the front.
-Mm-hmm.
-[Machu] You're right.
-[chattering on radio]
-[Machu] Yes!
[Shime] I see a station.
-[Machu chuckles]
-[Genta] You sure?
-Oh, a squirrel!
-[Machu] Where?
[Shime] Where is it?
[Genta] See the squirrel?
It's by the tracks. Right there.
Did we pass a station?
I was wrong.
Turns out it's a lodge, not a station.
[Machu] What a nice breeze.
[conductor, on radio, in English]
Train 265 to the dispatcher. Over.
-[brakes squeak]
-[engine hissing]
We'll leave out of here at 12:45.
[Genta] 12:45.
We're gonna want all the passengers
back on the train by 12:35 at the latest.
[Genta] All right.
And I'll, uh, be letting you guys know
about some sights
and things like that.
And we can show you
a couple really great views from up here.
Sound good?
-[all] Okay. Yeah. Okay.
-All right.
[♪ upbeat music playing]
Oh, yeah.
-[in Japanese] Whoa, how nice. I love it.
-[in English] Oh, yeah.
[whoops]
[♪ music continues]
[Machu, in Japanese] How refreshing!
[in English] Yeah.
-[Shime, in Japanese] Is it cold?
-The water feels amazing.
-Wanna come in?
-Like, actually?
Gotta take off my shoes then.
It's cold!
-[laughs] It feels amazing.
-[Shime] That's cold!
[Genta] Oh, the camera, the camera…
[Machu, in English] Yeah.
[in Japanese] Whoa.
[in English] Oh, yeah.
[in Japanese] Here, Shime.
Wash your face with this.
[♪ music stops]
-Don't you want to blow the whistle?
-That sounds nice.
Oh, sign me on. Heck yes!
The train ride was so thrilling.
The breeze was amazing.
The scenery was to die for.
-The breeze felt nice on my skin.
-[Genta] Mm-hmm.
It was simply the best.
I had three years' worth of fun
out in the wild.
-[Shime] Three years?
-Three years' worth?
Only three years? No more than that?
-Make that five. [laughs]
-[Genta laughs]
Yahoo. Try saying it.
Yahoo.
-Yahoo.
-Your turn.
Yeah?
This was a load of fun.
-Right?
-Yeah, it was so refreshing.
[Machu] We took in a breathtaking view
from the bridge too.
The bridge was my favorite.
And those tall rock walls.
It was a sight to behold.
The rear compartments looked really slick
rounding that huge curve.
-You mean the train?
-Yeah.
-I feel you.
-It was amazing.
-There's nothing like it.
-It was great.
This was good. I'm glad
we had this experience with the train.
[♪ gentle music playing]
Don't you want to blow the whistle?
-Make it go, "choo-choo."
-I wanted to make the train go choo-choo.
-We can try asking?
-Let's at least ask.
-There's no harm in asking.
-Yep.
-We'll say we didn't get a chance earlier.
-Yeah.
-[Machu] Wonder if they'll let us?
-[Genta] There's a chance.
-[passenger, in English] Hello.
-[all] Hello.
[in Japanese]
The front car is way up ahead.
[Shime laughs]
True that.
This rest area is incredibly nice, huh?
-It's chill.
-Isn't it chill? What?
Let's all sprint…
-[Machu] We'll race to the front…
-[Shime] Yeah, wanna race?
-…then say… [in English] Let's go!
-[in Japanese] Let's do it.
-[Genta] I'm down.
-Okay.
-Yeah? You won't leave us hanging?
-[Genta] I bet he'll run with us.
-I'll follow you the best I can.
-Then let's do it.
-Promise, okay?
-Okay.
-We're gonna race.
-Bring it on.
Ready, go. Zoom!
What's up?
I'm feeling the groove.
I'm in the mood to dash.
-You went all out?
-I did.
Look at this crowd.
They must be here
to look at the steam locomotive.
-Oh, you think?
-Yep.
[♪ music ends]
[conductor, in English] Four whistles
to get everybody back on the train.
-Okay.
-Russell's gonna blow the first
then each of you guys will take a turn
doing one whistle, okay?
-All right.
-Right. Watch your step going up there.
Okay, guys?
[Genta] Right.
[conductor] Watch your step
going up there. All right, guys?
-Thank you so much. All right.
-Yeah, thank you.
[in Japanese] Whoo-hoo!
[in English] Yeah!
[Genta, in Japanese]
I'm gonna blow the whistle!
-I'm stoked.
-We're here.
[Russell, in English] Okay. So,
the more you pull it, the louder it gets.
-Okay.
-So, I'll only pull a little bit
-because there's so many people around.
-[Machu] Okay, got it.
[train whistle blowing]
You're gonna hold it for like, three…
two or three seconds.
-Like-Like that? Okay.
-Right. Yep. Yep, just like that.
-[Shime, in Japanese] Whoa.
-Ready? Go.
[train whistle blowing]
-Whoa.
-[Shime] Nice!
-[Genta] Amazing!
-[Machu] Just wow.
[Shime] What an experience.
We did it!
-Ready?
-[Russell, in English] Yeah.
[train whistle blowing]
[Russell] Yeah.
[in Japanese] Welp, I'm up.
[train whistle blowing]
-[Genta, Machu, Shime whoop]
-[Russell, in English] Yeah.
-Thank you so much.
-[Shime] Thank you.
-[Genta] Yeah. Thank you.
-[Shime] It was so great.
-[Genta, in Japanese] This is crazy.
[Machu] Whoa. [laughs]
[Shime, in English] Good experience.
[Genta, in Japanese]
Everyone's gathered around.
-[Machu, in English] Thank you so much.
-[Genta] Appreciate it.
[Shime] Wow.
[Genta, in Japanese] Here they come.
It made me a tad emotional.
[Machu] Heck yes.
That was exhilarating.
-[Genta] I'm satisfied.
-I'm so glad we asked.
-Who knew the train whistles were so loud?
-[Genta] Right?
-It really rang out!
-[Machu] It was so loud.
-It was crazy.
-[Genta, in English] Thank you so much.
-Thank you so much.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
[in Japanese] Man, was that fun or what?
They're all coming.
-Everyone's gathering around.
-Yeah.
-Because of our whistle.
-The train went, "choo-choo."
Say cheese.
[camera shutter clicks]
Translated by Megumi Hunter